# ERNEST POUGH

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### CONTACT DETAILS

Email: poughe@gmail.com

l inkedIn·

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ernestpough/

GitHub:

https://github.com/Poughe

Portfolio:

https://ernestpough.dev/

# **SUMMARY**

Focused and quick-learning Software Engineer with over ten years of United States Army Reserve experience in a variety of technical roles in engineering and electronics. I am looking to join a team building projects for a mission driven organization.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- CSS3/HTML5
- JavaScript
- Node.is
- Express
- MongoDB
- React
- SEO Optimization
- DNS Setting
- Web Hosting
- Responsive Web Development
- Browser Developer Tools
- Git/GitHub
- Java

### MILITARY SKILLS

- Familiar with frequently used IC/Government databases and tools
- Read and understand electrical schematics, wiring diagrams, panels, and meters
- U.S. Army Power Generation (91D) Course
- U.S. Army HUMINT (35M) Course
- CPR/First-Aid

#### **EDUCATION**

Northern Virginia Community College

Computer Science/General Studies (Double Major) | JAN 2020 - Present

- -CGPA: 3.7
- -Dean's List Student
- -Officer in campus Coding Club

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Engineer**

#### RESILIENT CODERS | JUL 2021-Present

- Collaborated with teams of developers to design and build responsive full stack web applications using best practices
- Built semantically structured full stack web applications for mobile and desktop device
- Maintained detailed git history for all projects used GitHub in a team environment
- Created various logo designs and multiple page layouts
- Utilized excellent interpersonal skills with coworkers
- Adapted guickly to project outcomes
- Maintained detailed git history for all projects and used GitHub in a team environment

#### Recent Projects:

- <u>We Care</u> FullStack Application A web application connecting volunteer mentors in a variety of professions to underrepresented youth that share interests in those professions.
- Petstagram FullStack Application A social media application that allows users to share their favorite pictures of pets.
- Gardner-Grounds FullStack Application Local coffee shop web application to track customer fulfillment
- <u>Casino Roulette</u> FullStack Application The classic Roulette casino game
- <u>Weather App</u> API focused Application Get local weather when you type in your city

#### Freelance Full-Stack Web Developer

OPEN TO NEW CLIENTS | AUG 2021 - Present

#### **Tactical Power Generation Specialist**

US ARMY RESERVES | DEC 2010 - Present

- Deployment 2020: In support of Covid-19 Pandemic Relief Efforts
- Leads and trains teams of up to 45 soldiers in both classroom and practical application settings on HUMINT, power generation and basic soldier functions.
- Trains in conflict resolution and in managing large groups of people
- Leads groups up to 20 in size to accomplish various missions ranging from detainee operations to organizing inventory for a battalion sized element

#### **Operations Supervisor**

REPUBLIC SERVICES | AUG 2019 - NOV 2019

 Monitored and audited compressed natural gas vehicles, maintained 100% accountability of \$20M in company assets

#### Field Transportation Specialist

AMAZON | MAY 2017 - APR 2019

 Conduct daily coordination with fulfillment center operations departments, transportation peers and carriers to ensure all trailers arrive and depart on time with zero defects through various data entries